Hi there. I'm Mike.
I'm Josh.
We would like to welcome you to this course on data visualization.
Data visualization is vital in multiple areas of the data analysis process.
Two main topics are covered in this course.
Exploratory data visualizations are used to understand
the structure of your data faster than statistics would be able to load.
This type of visualization is used once you are
ready to start investigating your gathered data.
Explanatory data visualizations, on the other hand,
are created at the end of your analysis.
This type of visualization is used to convey your findings to others or to tell a story.
This course will go over more than just how to code to create your visualizations.
You'll also learn about the design of visualizations from
choosing the right plot type to selecting appropriate variable encoding.
You will learn to create visualizations that are clear not just for you,
but also for others.
Data visualization is probably my favorite part of the data analysis process.
It is always exciting to observe visualizations that generate new insights.
By going through this course,
you'll be able to use data visualization techniques to enhance your data analysis work.