In this course, you will make use of two Python Visualization Libraries.
Matplotlib and Seaboard.
You will also make use of plotting functions built into the pandas library,
which is a general data analysis package not explicitly just for data visualization.
Often, when choosing a tool to work with,
there's a trade-off between flexibility and productivity.
On one end, you have a tool that has a high amount of flexibility.
Matplotlib falls on this end of the spectrum.
The versatility of Matplotlib,
allows it to be used for nearly any kind of visualization you care to create.
But this versatility, can come with a lot of verbosity.
There are some common plots like bar charts,
that require a large amount of code to be written.
The fact that you sometimes need to be very specific about how plots are
created can make it hard to quickly explore your data with matplotlib alone.
If you're looking to be productive,
and need to be generating many plots with little code,
Libraries like seaborne and Pandas can come in handy.
These libraries contain a lot of
convenience functions to quickly generate plots of your data.
However, the plot types afforded by these libraries are not exhaustive.
So on their own, they're not as flexible as matplotlib.
Together, the strengths of these libraries are complementary.
For the most part, you can expect to use Pandas and
Seaboard to perform initial explorations of your data.
You may then want to use matplotlib to customize your plots,
or generate plots not covered by these other libraries.